<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/vietworld/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/vietworld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-09T22:12:44+03:00</updated><id>/vietworld/feed.xml</id><title type="html">vietworld</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First programming language</title><link href="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/08/first-prog-lang.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First programming language" /><published>2019-08-08T23:37:05+03:00</published><updated>2019-08-08T23:37:05+03:00</updated><id>/vietworld/tech/2019/08/08/first-prog-lang</id><content type="html" xml:base="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/08/first-prog-lang.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-programming-language&quot;&gt;First programming language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting out, many people are confused with what programming language to start with. I will try to clear this confusion once and for all by giving my 2 cents on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that the programming language does not matter that much. Howver, one will always have a special attachment to their first language. In my case that is JavaScript. Since then I’ve written on a handful of other languages but nothing can beat that initial feeling of accomplishment when first solving a hard task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, one should choose one language and stick with it for a while to learn its quirks and specifics. Some may argue that it is best to start with C or C++ but I do not think that this is a good idea. When starting out, a lot of people feel intimidated by writing code. If we add a non-beginner friendly language to the picture things can get rough pretty quick. I have friends who have rediscovered their passion for programming after switching to an easier language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I think it is better to start with something like JavaScript or Python where the syntax is easy and memory management and other things are happening behind the curtains. Thus, one can learn the problem solving methodology that will help them onwards with their careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, once one feels comfortable enough in their basic understanding of the language, I think that it is essential to move and try different languages to broaden their horizons. C/C++ are the go to place for learning memory management and haskell is among the best options for functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the most important thing is to start writing code and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First programming language When starting out, many people are confused with what programming language to start with. I will try to clear this confusion once and for all by giving my 2 cents on the topic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My CS50 Journey</title><link href="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/07/cs50-journey.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My CS50 Journey" /><published>2019-08-07T23:37:05+03:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T23:37:05+03:00</updated><id>/vietworld/tech/2019/08/07/cs50-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/07/cs50-journey.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-cs50&quot;&gt;What is CS50?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there is a limitless number of online courses and tutorials. CS50 is one of the best ones out there that will push you to the limit and ultimately make you a better programmer. It is a Harvard Course that one can take for free in edx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has 9 weeks of content with different programming tasks. In the beginning, it covers the basics of C programming where you learn about functions, pointers and structs. Afterwards it moves to Python and Javascript. It is really challenging because the tasks are really different and made in such a way that you have to think to solve them. They are different and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is a hard course and quite time-consuming, I can not recommend it enough. It helped me a lot on my journey. CS50 shows the different faces of computer science and by the end you may find which one suits you the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/cs50s-introduction-to-computer-science&quot;&gt;Start right now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is CS50?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Machine Learning is the future?</title><link href="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/05/machine-learning-future.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Machine Learning is the future?" /><published>2019-08-05T23:37:05+03:00</published><updated>2019-08-05T23:37:05+03:00</updated><id>/vietworld/tech/2019/08/05/machine-learning-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="/vietworld/tech/2019/08/05/machine-learning-future.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-machine-learning-is-the-future&quot;&gt;Why Machine Learning is the future?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently living in a very exciting age. Things that weren’t thought possible are happening.
This is the age of technology, the age of innovation. Machine Learning is a vital part in all of this.
But what is ML? Is it just a trendy word or is is something that may change everything as we know it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to wikipedia Machine learning (ML) is the scientific study of algorithms and statistical models that computer systems use to perform a specific task without using explicit instructions, relying on patterns and inference instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this may sound a bit too dry, ML is one of the most astonishing subsets of computer science.
It is a fusion between mathematics, statistics and programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algorithms can know predict outcomes without the intervention of human beings. Some people are afraid that this technology is disrupting industries. While they are correct in a way, this isn’t a bad thing because new jobs will emerge. If we think about it jobs such as Data Scientist, Machine Learning Engineer, Digital marketer are entirely new. This is a logical step and it has happened countless times before. Every industrial revolution has been followed by new jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;types-of-machine-learning-algorithms&quot;&gt;Types of Machine learning algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three different ML algorithms available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supervised learning - In these algorithms, we have both the input and the output. We train the algorithm so that it can predict what the output will be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsupervised learning - In unsupervised learning, we have only the input and the algorithm learns from plain examples, determing data patterns on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reinforcement Learning - Simillar to unsupervised learning with the difference that we can give a negative or positive feedback to the output. In human words, it is just like learning by trial and error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Why Machine Learning is the future? We are currently living in a very exciting age. Things that weren’t thought possible are happening. This is the age of technology, the age of innovation. Machine Learning is a vital part in all of this. But what is ML? Is it just a trendy word or is is something that may change everything as we know it?</summary></entry></feed>